Guide to the Elmer E. Robinson Americana, 1765-1950 M0002
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE OF AMERICAN GOVERNMENT, CIVILIAN AND MILITARY FIGURES., 1778-1941.
  - ROOT, ELIHU, (1) (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - to R. L. Wilbur., 1924, May 13.; TLS
  - SANGRAIN, PIERRE TOURTILLE, (14) (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - DS Proposes formation of an American company for obtaining whale oil at request of Lafayette. With typed translation and bibliographical information., 1875, May 7.
  - SCHMITZ, E. E., (1) (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - TNS to Norton G. Wells. Ordering clothes for earthquake relief worker., 1906, April 28.
  - SEYMOUR, HORATIO, (2) (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - to Charles E. Taylor., 1863, Dec. 3.; ALS
  - SHEPPARD, MORRIS F. * RUSSELL H. DAY, (1) (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - DS Special Orders creating a board of survey., 1865, March 28.
  - SHERMAN, WILLIAM TECUMSEH, (9) (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Ptd. invitation to marriage of Sherman's daughter. Cover in Sherman's hand., 1874, Oct. 1.
    - to Gen. Guersin., 1879, May 16.; ALS
    - to Gen. Guersin., 1882, Oct. 5.; ALS
    - Ptd. calling card, invitation, advance advertisement of an article., N.D.
  - SPINNER, F. E., (4) (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - to Samuel P. Benson, Gen. Blair and Gov. Chase; Lincoln's opinion and controversy in Cabinet. [with auction note]., 1864, July 19.; ALS
  - STEVENS, THADDEUS, (1) (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - to [?]., 1867, Aug. 9.; ANS
  - TANEY, ROGER B., (1) (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Cover to Mr. Seldon, Marshal, D.C., ND.
  - TAYLOR, ZACHARY, (2) (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - DS Apptmt. also signed by William Ballard Preston., 1849, April 4.
  - TROGANOVSKY, A., (2) (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - to R. L. Wilbur., 1935, Feb. 1.; TLS
  - TRUMAN, HARRY S., (19) (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 8.; TLS
    - Typescript sgd. of speech., 1950, Oct. 17.
    - to Elmer E. Robinson., 1950, Oct. 23.; TLS
    - Autograph and cover., 1955, Jan. 13.
  - TUMULTY, JOSEPH PATRICK, (1) (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - to R. L. Wilbur., 1932, March 12.; TLS
  - TYLER, JOHN, (2) (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - to Joshua Huntington. Request for lead., 1779, Aug. 8.; ALS
    - ADS John Braddick to Joshua Huntington. Receipt for lead. [Auction note.], 1779, Aug. 9.
  - VAN BUREN, MARTIN, (1) (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - to John M. Niles., N.D.; ALS
  - WARTS, HENRY A., (1) (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - DS Petition soliciting an apptment. Sgd. by several, incl. Robert Morris, Mayor., 1853, April 19.
  - WASHINGTON, BUSHROD, (6) (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - to Tobias Lear requesting articles for Mrs. Washington; has written to the General about a position. TS + bibl. information., 1789, July 1.; ALS
  - WILSON, WOODROW, (1) (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - to James D. Phelan., 1916, Jan. 11.; TLS
- MISCELLANEOUS DOCUMENTS.
  Legal and economic subjects; early American period.
  - COMMERCE, ETC.: EARLY AMERICAN, (10) (Box 2, Folder 115)
    Five bills, orders and receipts dealing with purchase of iron for cannon. Signatures include: Joshua Huntington, Jeremiah Harris, Robert Livingston, and John Calder.
- SIGNERS OF THE DECLARATION OF INDEPENDENCE.
  - BARTLETT, JOSIAH., (3)
    - ADS land transfer., 1770, Sept. 19.
    - NS., 1777, May 2.
  - CARROLL, CHARLES of Carrollton, (3)
    Two autographs. SEE ALSO: OVERSIZED FOLDERS.
  - CLYMER, GEORGE, (2)
    - Signature on verso of promisory note by Henry Clymer., 1802, May 12.
  - ELLERY, WILLIAM, (4)
    - financial., 1788, July 3.; ANS
    - DS customs clearance., 1795, May 6, 7.
  - HANCOCK, JOHN., (2)
    - 1777, May 2., ANS.
    - Signed warrant., 1785, May 25.
  - HARRISON, BENJAMIN, (2)
    - DS., 1783, Aug. 29.
    - DS., 1784, June 30.
  - HEYWARD, THOMAS, JR., (3)
    - DS., 1783, Dec. 1.; Autograph.
  - HOPKINS, STEPHEN, (2)
    - to S. Chase., 1761, Aug. 14.; ANS
    - DS., 1763, Nov.
  - HOPKINSON, FRANCIS, (4)
    - Signed sight draft., 1778, Nov. 16.
    - DS., 1780, Dec. 25.
    - DS., 1783, Nov. 24.
  - HUNTINGTON, SAMUEL, (3)
    - LS., 1780, Dec. 22.
  - JEFFERSON, THOMAS SEE: OVERSIZED FOLDERS., (2)
    - McKEAN, THOMAS., (2)
    - DS., 1767, Aug. 28.
  - MORRIS, ROBERT., (2)
    - LS to William Whipple., 1783, June 22.
    - DS., 1787, Jan. 5.
  - MORTON, JOHN, (1)
    - DS., 1772, March 6.
  - ROSS, GEORGE, (3)
    - DS. Also Edward Ward., 1769, March 28.; Autograph.
  - RUTLEDGE, EDWARD, (4)
    - Autograph., 1771, Dec.
    - Writ., 1789, ADS.
  - SHERMAN, ROGER, (1)
    - Receipt DS., 1779, April.
  - WALTON, GEORGE, (5)
    - DS Subpoena. Sgd. by Wm. Houstoun., 1783, Oct. 1.
    - Petition sgd, by Isabella Chapman., 1792, March 28.
  - WILLIAMS, WILLIAM, (4)
    - to Mary Mason., 1763, Feb. 2.; ALS
    - AS endorsement on verso of deed., 1786, Dec. 11.
  - WOLCOTT, LASTER OLIVER, (6)
    - ADS., 1757.
    - ADS receipt., 1762, Feb. 17.
    - DS receipt for Marine Hospitals., 1799, Oct. 5.
  - ZOLL, JACOB, (2)
    - DS Agreement with James Wilson., 1795, Feb. 16.
- CONGRESSIONAL SIGNATURES.
  Members of House of Representatives and Senate listed alphabetically under each house. Mainly members of the 77th Congress.
  - MEMBERS OF CONGRESS: HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES: (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - BLAND, SCHUYLER OTIS, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS.
    - BLOOM, SOL, (1)
      - to Robinson., 1939, May 2.; TLS
    - BOLLES, STEPHEN, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 8.; TLS
    - BOLTON, FRANCIS P., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 8.; TLS
    - BRYSON, JOSEPH R., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS
    - CANNON, PAT, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 8.; TLS
    - CHENOWETH, J. EDGAR, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS
    - COCHRAN, JOHN J., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS
    - COLE, WILLIAM P. JR., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS
    - COOKE, MARY REBECCA, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 9.; TLS
    - [EDWARDS, DON - See: Box 1, Folder 33.]
    - ELLIS, CLYDE TAYLOR, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 8.; TLS
    - ENGLEBRIGHT, HARRY L., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 9.; TLS
    - FITZGERALD, WILLIAM J., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 8.; TLS
    - FORAND, AIME J., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS
    - FORD, LELAND M., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 9.; TLS
    - GEARHART, BERTRAND W., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS
    - HARRINGTON, VINCENT F., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 8.; TLS
    - HAVENNER, FRANCK R., (1)
      - to Robinson., 1939, May 5.; TLS
    - HOBBS, SAM, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS
    - JOHNSON, LUTHER A., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 9.; TLS
    - JONES, ROBERT F., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 14.; TLS
    - KEEFE, FRANK B., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 8.; TLS
    - KEFAUVER, ESTES, (1)
      - TLStto Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.
    - KOCIALKOWSKI, LEO, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS
    - KUNKEL, JOHN C., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 9.; TLS
    - LEAVY, CHARLES H., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 9.; TLS
    - MARTIN, THOMAS E., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS
    - MICHENER, EARL C., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 9.; TLS
    - NELSON, WILLIAM L., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 9.; TLS
    - NORTON, MARY T., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS
    - O'DAY, CAROLINE, (1)
      - TL sgd. by secy. to Rolph., 1941, May 7.
    - PAGAN, BOLIVAR, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 8.; TLS
    - PATMAN, WRIGHT, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 8.; TLS
    - PIERCE, WALTER M., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 9.; TLS
    - PLUMLEY, CHARLES A., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS
    - RAYBURN, SAM, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 9.; TLS
    - RIZLEY, ROSS, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 14.; TLS
    - SCHUETZ, LEONARD W., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 8.; TLS
    - STEARNS, FOSTER, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 9.; TLS
    - SULLIVAN, JOHN B., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 21.; TLS
    - SUMNERS, HATTON W., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 8.; TLS
    - WELCH, RICHARD J., (1)
      - to Robinson., 1939, May 4.; TLS
    - WENE, ELMER H., (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 15.; TLS
    - VOORHIS, JERRY, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 12.; TLS
    - YOUNGDAHL, OSCAR, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1941, May 7.; TLS
  - MEMBERS OF CONGRESS: SENATE: (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - AUSTIN, WARREN R., (1)
      - 1941, May 7., TLS.
    - BAILEY, JOSIAH W., (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
    - BILBO, THEODORE G., (1)
      - 1941, May 7., TLS.
    - BUNKER, BERKELEY, (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
    - BURTON, HAROLD H., (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
    - CAPPER, ARTHUR, (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
    - DAVIS, JAMES J., (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
    - DOWNEY, SHERIDAN, (1)
      - 1941, May 7., TLS.
    - GREEN, THEODORE F., (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
    - HERRING, CLYDE, (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
    - JOHNSON, HIRAM, (2)
      - 1940, July 12., TLS.
      - 1940, Dec. 7., TLS.
    - MEAD, JAMES M., (1)
      - 1941, May 13., TLS.
    - MITCHELE, M. W., (1)
      - 1941, May 7., TLS.
    - MOSES, GEORGE H., (1)
      - N.D., TLS.
    - MURDOCK, ABE, (1)
      - 1941, May 12., TLS.
    - SHIPSTEAD, HENRIK, (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
    - SMATHERS, WILLIAM H., (1)
      - 1941, May 9., TLS.
    - STEWART, TOM, (1)
      - 1941, May 7., TLS.
    - THOMAS, ELBERT D., (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
    - THOMAS, ELMER, (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
    - TUNNELL, JAMES M., (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
- MISCELLANEOUS SIGNATURES.
  California officials; U.S. officials; one international statesman; two items re Garfield's and Wilson's health.
  - CALIFORNIA OFFICIALS: (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - PARDEE, GEORGE C., (1)
      - to I. W. Lees., 1902, Aug. 29.; TLS
    - RICHARDSON, FRIEND, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1932, April 7.; TLS
    - ROLPH, JAMES, (1)
      - to Thomas Rolph., 1932, Feb. 8.; TLS
  - U.S. OFFICIALS: (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - GASTON, HERBERT E., (1)
      - 1941, May 9., TLS.
    - HULL, CORDELL, (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
    - JACKSON, ROBERT H., (1)
      - 1941, May 9., TLS.
    - JONES, JESSE H., (1)
      - 1941, May 12., TLS.
    - KNOX, FRANK, (1)
      - 1941, May 19., TLS.
    - McCRILLIS, W. H., (1)
      - 1941, May 9., TLS.
    - McINTYRE, M. H., (1)
      - 1941, May 10., TLS.
    - PERKINS, FRANCIS, (1)
      - 1941, May 8., TLS.
    - STIMSON, HENRY L., (1)
      - 1941, May 13., TLS.
    - WALKER, FRANK C., (1)
      - 1941, May 9., TLS.
    - WALLACE, H. A., (1)
      - 1941, June 10., TLS.
    - WILLKIE, WENDELL L., (1)
      - 1940, Sept. 11., TLS.
  - International Statemen
    - HAMMARSKJOLD, DAG, (1) (Box 2, Folder 121)
      - to Robinson., 1955, Dec. 9.; TLS
  - MISCELLANY, (9) (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Seven bulletins re Garfield's health from doctors in attendance., dated Aug. 19 - Sept. 8
    - T/ALS Will to Helen re Wilson's health., 1919, Oct. 10.
- DOCUMENTS OF CALIFORNIA AND U.S. OFFICIALS.
  Chronologically arranged within category.
  - DOCUMENTS: CALIFORNIA GOVERNORS: (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
    - BIGLER, JOHN. DS also sgd. by James W. Denver., 1854, Nov. 17.
    - HAIGHT, HENRY H. DS and sgd. by Jas. M. Glen and H.L. Nichols., 1869, May 21.
      - -- DS and sgd. by Thos. N. - Cazneau and H. L. Nichols., 1871, Aug. 31.
    - PACHECO, ROMUALDO. DS and sgd. by L.H. Foote and Drury Melone., 1875, March 8.
    - IRWIN, WILLIAM, P.F. Walsh, Thos. Beck., 1877, Dec. 6.
    - PERKINS, GEORGE C. Daniel M. Burns, James W. Shanklin., 1882, Aug. 29.
    - STONEMAN, GEORGE. Thomas L. Thompson, H. J. Willey., 1883, Aug. 10.
    - 6. Stoneman, George Thomas L. Thompson, H.J. Willey., 1883, Aug. 10.
  - DOCUMENTS - U.S. PRESIDENTS, ETC. I (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
    - 1. Washington, George 1732 - 1799
      - D.S. Henry Knox, John Stagg, Jr., 1793, Mar. 19.
    - 2. Monroe, James 1758 - 1831
      - D.S. [Josiah?] Meigs., 1817, Oct. 6.
    - 3. Adams, John Quincy 1767 - 1848
      - D.S. Geo. Graham., 1825, Apr. 14.
    - 4. Jackson, Andrew 1767 - 1845
      - D.S. Geo. Graham., 1828, Mar. 23.
      - D. Signed by sec., E. Brown., 1835, Sep. 30.
    - 5. Van Buren, Martin 1782 - 1862
      - D.S. Apptmt. of Stewart Newell as consul. John Forsyth., 1837, Oct. 12.
      - 3 Ds signed by sec. M. Van Buren, Jr. [Jos. S. Nilsen or Wilson?]., 1839, Aug. 1.
      - D. signed by sec. M. Van Buren, Jr. [Jos. S. Nilsen or Wilson?]., 1840, Nov. 10.
    - 6. Tyler, John 1790 - 1862
      - D. [signed by sec.?] J. Williamson., 1841, June 25.
      - D.S. Apptmt. of Charles Thompson, Jr. as consul. Daniel Webster, [Migl. Barbachan?]., 1843, Mar. 3.
    - 7. Taylor, Zachary 1784 - 1850
      - D. [signed by sec.?]., 1850, Jan. 18.
      - D. [signed by sec.?]., 1848 - 1850, Feb. 1.
    - 8. Fillmore, Milard 1800 - 1874
      - D.S. William A. Graham., 1851, Apr. 11.
    - 9. Pierce, Franklin 1804 - 1869
      - D. signed by sec., Jn. Granger., 1853, Dec. 1.
      - D. signed by sec., Jos. S. Wilson., 1854, Sep. 15.
      - D. signed by sec., Jn. Granger., 1855, May 1.
      - D. signed by sec., Jn. Granger., 1855, Oct. 1.
      - D.S. Jefferson Davis, Samuel Cooper., 1856, Apr. [19? or 30].
  - DOCUMENTS - U.S. PRESIDENTS, ETC. II (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
    - 1. Buchanan, James 1791 - 1868
      - D. [signed by sec.?]., 1857, Sep. 1.
      - D.S. Isaac Toucey, Wm. R. Moran., 1860, Sep. 5.
    - 2. Lincoln, Abraham 1809 - 1865
      - D.S. Edwin M. Stanton., 1863, Mar. 4.
    - 3. Seward, William Henry 1801 - 1872
      - D.S. (passport)., 1862, Sep. 30.
    - 4. Johnson, Andrew 1808 - 1875
      - D.S. Edwin M. Stanton, E.D. Townsend., 1866, Sep. 10.
    - 5. Grant, Ulysses Simpson 1822 - 1885
      - D. signed by S.D. Williamson., 1872, Nov. 15.
      - D. signed by S.D. Williamson., 1874, Feb. 3.
      - D.S. William W. Belknap, E.D. Townsend., 1875, Mar. 12.
      - D. signed by D.O. [Cone] & S.W. Clark., 1877, Mar. 1.
    - 6. Hayes, Rutherford B. 1822 - 1893
      - D.S. Richard W. Thompson, Wm. P. Moran., 1880, May 22.
      - D. signed by sec. & S.W. Clarke., 1881, Feb. 17.
    - 7. Arthur, Chester A. 1830 - 1886
      - D. [signed by sec.?] & S.W. Clarke., 1883, Feb. 3.
      - D.S. Henry F. French., 1883, Feb. 17.
  - DOCUMENTS - U.S. PRESIDENTS, ETC. III (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
    - 1. Cleveland, Stephen Grover 1837 - 1908
      - D.S. Adlai Ewing Stevenson, 1886, Aug. 26.
    - 2. Harrison, Benjamin 1833 - 1901
      - D.S. J.E. Walker, 1889, Aug. [13 or 30?].
      - D.S. Stephen B. Elkins., 1892, Jan. 7.
    - 3. McKinley, William 1843 - 1901
      - D.S. Wm. [UNK] arry [Langen?], 1901, Aug. 8.
    - 4. Roosevelt, Theodore 1858 - 1919
      - D.S. Elihu Root., 1906, May 14.
    - 5. Taft, William Howard 1857 - 1930
      - D.S. Jacob M. Dickinson., 1911, May 19.
    - 6. Wilson, Woodrow 1856 - 1924
      - D.S. Franklin D. Roosevelt., 1916, Jan. 25.
      - D.S. Josephus Daniels., 1916, May 27.
      - D.S. Newton D. Baker., 1916, Nov. 8.
    - 7. Harding, Warren Gamaliel 1865 - 1923
      - D.S. Hubert Work., 1922, Aug. 2.
    - 8. Coolidge, Calvin 1872 - 1933
      - D.S. Harry S. New., 1927, Feb. 12.
    - 9. Hoover, Herbert Clark 1874 - 1964
      - D.S. Walter F. Brown., 1931, Jan. 28.
    - 10. Truman, Harry S. 1884 -
      - D.S. David Bruce, 1952, June 29.
    - CLINTON, GEORGE, 1790, Feb.
      (Oversize)